Alie Brubaker

Newburgh, IN 763-269-1213 | findingalberta@gmail.com LinkedIn | Github | Tech Blog | Portfolio Website

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Building experience with Ruby on Rails and JavaScript based programming. Background in non-tech industries with many years of team leadership and goal-oriented metric achievement in retail consumables and sales. Primary focus in team-building and training. Very interested in working as a DEI ambassador or leader.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Trained in JavaScript and React, with Styled Components for styling, and Ruby on Rails using SQLite3 or PostgreSQL.

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Rainbow - Github Demo

A social media site with an emphasis on being a place for LGBTQ+ people to gather and share their lives

- Constructed a Rails backend in a monorepo with a React frontend
- Implemented a React library to create an infinite scroll reverse engineered from class components for use in functional components
- Used the Bcrypt Ruby gem to create backend authorization and authentication on client-side input for secure credential storage
- Learned to use the JSON-API Serializer to streamline backend operation with Rails Active Storage
- Applied Active Storage to maintain a database table of user uploaded image files as avatars and posts
- Built a Facebook-like UI/UX in React using Styled-Components and React-Bootstrap

DnD Flatbase - Github - Frontend | Backend Demo

A full stack web application for players of Dungeons & Dragons to create, store, and modify character sheets

- Leveraged Ruby using Active Record and Sinatra to build a back-end to store data in a SQL database
- Utilized React to build a very clean interface for the user with attractive features which mimic the DnDBeyond UX
- Handbuilt the styling for the UX in React with Styled-Components which created a sleek user experience

Flatify - Github Demo

A close one-for-one UI clone of the Spotify web application

Constructed an extremely close homage to Spotify's signature look in React using Styled-Components

EXPERIENCE

Toyota Motors Manufacturing Indiana

Production Team Member

Princeton, IN 06/2019 - 05/2022

- Installed parts on unibody vehicles in very fast paced manufacturing environment
- Focused on continuous improvement of process and error free production

Total Wine & More Wine Supervisor/M1

Minnetonka, MN 06/2016 - 04/2019

• Improved profile wine sales by 6% on \$11 million in top-line wine sales and 3% on \$ 3.5million In top-line spirits sales

- Performed in manager role focusing on day-to-day operation
- Improved in-store education from 8th in market to 3rd

EDUCATION

Flatiron School Remote

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript/React program

06/2022 - 10/2022

Attended for five semesters

Minneapolis, MN

University of Minnesota

08/2004 - 05/2006